Chance Payne

 ♀ Sparks, Nevada, United States
 □ cmpayne5@gmail.com
 □ (916) 496-4863
 ➡ in/chance-payne/

SUMMARY

Experienced Software Engineer with knowledge of a wide range of platforms, languages, and technologies. Constantly learning new technologies and will do what it takes to get the job done. Currently specializing in **Android Development** with past professional experience in **Full Stack Web Development** and **User Experience Design**. Quick learner, picking up skills in **iOS development** and **React**.

SKILLS

Android Development: Java, Kotlin, SQL

Web Development: Javascript, HTML, Node.js, Angular, Java (Spring), Kotlin (yay cross compilation!)

EXPERIENCE

Senior Android Engineer

Wealthfront

Remote, January 2020 - December 2022

- ·Work with Product and Design teams to design experiences for users all over the app
- ·Work with cross platform engineering teams to implement these experiences
- · Communicate with teams when issues with the design or implementation were uncovered and work together to find solutions
- · Work with the Android platform team to monitor builds and improve the infrastructure of the app

Lead Android Instructor

Lambda School

Remote, May 2018 - November 2019

- · Independently designed, built, and taught a 4 month Android Instruction program that encompassed 40 aspiring developers
- · Designed and wrote over 100 apps for demo projects and evaluation challenges
- · Coordinated student competence evaluations through 3rd party with positive feedback, showing a high pass rate
- ·Onboarded and trained additional instructors and curriculum developers to convert material from Java to Kotlin

Software Engineer

VPI Technology Group

Draper, UT, June 2014 - June 2018

- · Developed multiple **Android** apps to communicate and control external devices over **Bluetooth**
- · Updated and maintain **Android** apps to control hardware devices over **Wi-Fi** and **USB** serial interfaces
- · Created C#, Node.js, and Python applications to control devices over different types of hardware interfaces
- · Designed **User Interfaces** for various projects

Owner/Operator

Business Printing Solutions

Folsom, CA, November 2010 - November 2012

- · Worked closely with clients to **design** a product to meet their specific needs
- · Designed and print marketing and internal documents using Adobe Creative Suite

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Utah Valley University

Orem, UT, January 2014 - May 2017

Course Highlights

Advanced Web Programming · Node.js, Angular, JQuery, Bootstrap, React

Built a variety of projects illustrating the strengths and weaknesses of different technologies

Principles and Patterns of Software Design · Software Architecture and Design

Learned and used multiple Gang of Four design patterns

PROJECTS

Radiological Detection System · User Interface

Designed and built UI and assets for Multimillion-Dollar Radiation Detection System for the US Armed Forces

Smart Sprinkler System · Node.js, Angular, SQL

Built a server to connect to test devices being manufactured, allow for remote monitoring, and store test results for analysis

Wireless Projector App · Android, Java, iOS

Took over an app that connects to a web server running on mini projector, improved the user interface and experience.

Bluetooth Android Apps · Android, Bluetooth, Java

Worked on apps to interact with devices over bluetooth including an Alarm Clock, Power Tools, a Smart Battery, and a Smart Lock